Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Tim
Dylan Show. Recorded on the day the
market is dipping,
crashing. There's blood in the water.
The tariffs have arrived. Uh Donald
Trump is uh putting
tariffs on many countries
to bring back manufacturing to America.
It's a gambit. It's a risky gambit. We
are primarily a podcastingbased economy.
We are a hot take economy. We are an
opinion driven economy. We do not make
anything anymore except uh takes. We are
a
grievanced economy. We are a
ragebased economy. And that is we're
shifting now. And it's painful from an
economy based on uh uh people's uh uh
thoughts and feelings to an economy now
hopefully based on people manufacturing
things and going back to the factory.
Get back in the factory is what Trump's
hoping. He's hoping that people will uh
walk back into the factories and start
making stuff made in the USA.
you know, people be they're proud. They
work with their hands again. They get
into it again. They get on that assembly
line again. And I don't know. I mean,
maybe that happens. I'm skeptical. I'm a
little
skeptical, but you know what? Maybe it
happens. Maybe we learn to to live with
less. Maybe we learn to live with
less. We don't need all these things. is
we we we we instead of all these things
that are
cheap, you get a a job in a factory and
you work there all day every day and you
have camaraderie with the other workers
at the
factory. That's the hope
here. Uh you know the the softball team
and the cookout and the block party and
we bring America back where that's the
hope. The hope is that you work all day
at the factory and then you have friends
there and you all go together and raise
your children and you some one of you
coaches the team and then it's it's that
America we all read about and hoped for
and none of us really ever lived in but
it comes back and people are excited
have pride you I work we I work at the
factory and I make the stuff and the
stuff is
good. And we derive a sense of national
pride from
that. And one and there's and you don't
have a million cars. You have one car
that the family uses and everyone has to
decide who gets the car when you might
you're not going to afford a car
anymore. You get one car for the family
of six or seven people. Grandpa,
grandma, mom, dad, the three kids. You
have one vehicle. You have one TV. It
goes back to fighting over what are we
watching. We've lost that with cheap
goods. The rage that you felt when
someone had the TV in the living room
and you didn't and you wanted to watch
something. It's all coming back is my
point. Those moments we lost fighting
with each other. Now everyone's got a
TV, everyone's got a phone, everyone's
got a car. there's no sense of of
togetherness. But now there's will be a
sense of together when everyone has one
thing, an entire family has one thing
that everyone can fight over and rip
each other's faces off so that you all
decide as a f you argue as a family
about the merits of what shows on
Netflix you want to watch. Let's go see
some of these numbers here. They're a
little troubling. They're
disconcerting. The Dow's down about
1,400 points. S&P is down
4% as of
now. Nike fell 12%. So many of its
products are made outside of the United
States. You don't need Nikes. You don't
need them. There are other
shoes. There's other types of shoe other
than a Nike. United Airlines lost
10% because their customers are worried
about the global economy. You ain't
getting on the
plane. Nvidia saying
4.6%. Which they've already been losing,
but now their loss is down to
22%. I mean, all of these things you're
going to you're going to learn to live
without
traveling or shoes.
There's I don't know what to tell people
that need these things all the time to
be
happy. You don't need all of these
things to be happy all the time. You
just need to make do with
less. This is how you bring
back the America that we lost.
I'm telling
you, this is
what this is what people are are are
excited
about because there's too much uh [__]
People have too many
things. You don't need a
phone anymore like a
smartphone. All it does is pump your
head full of
craziness. You don't need Sell it. If
you have a smartphone right now, sell it
to a drug dealer who can use it. If
you're not a drug dealer, you don't need
a phone. It's the It's the way that we
treated pagers in the Oh, you have a
pager. Are you a drug dealer? That's
what it used to be. You had a cell
phone, you were a drug dealer. Now,
everyone needs a cell phone. By midday,
the S&P 500 lost
4.37%. The Nasdaq declined by 5.59%. and
the Dow. Most of this doesn't matter to
people because they're just broke and
they don't know what any of this means
and it doesn't mean anything to them.
But there are people that have the 401k,
that retirement plan and and that got
hammered cuz you're all invested. Okay,
we've erased trillions of dollars from
the US stock
market and this but you know you got to
stop thinking that more
money is making you
happier. It it actually could go the
opposite where some of the happiest
people I know are impoverished.
Have you seen a third world country and
all the kids are smiling and singing
songs? A lot of them are singing songs.
Bring up African children singing. Get
up. African children singing, please.
African children singing. Smiling and
singing. I don't want to see any of the
starvation. It depresses me. Singing.
Not the Well, okay. Well, look at this.
Look at this. Bring this up. I'm not
alone. This is what's going to happen
once everyone. Look at the What are we
talking about? Let's go.
It's a poor country.
When's the last time you've seen
Americans sing like this and be happy?
Never.
All right. All right. It's too it's you
know but but this is what I mean get up
other get up get up get up homeless
crackhead dancing because you need to
understand that your your wealth does
not define your level of
happiness. I'm telling you you have to
you have to divorce yourself from this
idea. Oh I I've got a big fat
retirement. We going to retire and see
the world.
Please give give me a white crackhead. I
don't want to be accused of racism. Get
a white Google white crackhead
dancing. I'm trying to prove to people
that you can be happy with less. Is this
a real crackhead or is it some sketch?
Get a real crackhead, please. A white
crackhead who is happy because we don't
need the things
anymore. And I think we're going to
we're gonna be we're gonna be
happy. The van life, people living in
vans, they're thrilled because they have
freedom. That's what we need. We don't
need this uh over
complicated thing where everybody's got
all this money and we're all I'm going
to retire Myrtle Beach, Florida. We're
going to have I'm going to play golf and
the little woman's going to drink wine.
No. Work. Work.
Work. Work gives you Get up. Just Google
happy factory. I want to see people in a
factory that are
happy. F. Get up. You
know, [__] What's that uh what's that
Broadway show where they're all singing
with the with the the Look, look. Just
show an image of this. Show how happy
they are. Get that up. Get that up. Look
at this. They're happy because the job
is well done. The job is well done. Put
it up. The job is well done. Look at
this. They're high-fiving. They're all
raising their hands. They're Who wants
to work more? Me. I want to work more.
Who wants to come in on their day off?
That's the question they just asked. I
want to come in on my day off. I'm proud
of what we make here. Look at that.
Elderly people with hard hats. That's
what I want to see more of in this
country. Elderly people with hard hats
on. Proud of what they do. You think
that guy wants to be in Myrtle Beach
playing golf? No. It's now a country
about work. It's now a country about
work. It was all this financial
trickery. Oh, the money's over here. The
money is over there. Where's the money
going? It's a game of monopoly. fake
real estate developers and foreign money
and everything. No, no, no, no, no. This
is a game now about uh work and
workhouses. Get up food, glorious food
from
Oliver. People misunderstand Oliver.
They go, "Oh, how depressing is it? It's
orphans. None of them have parents."
Sure. What it really is is people are
working and it's a sense of
community. It's a sense of community.
Let's This is what we're going back to.
That hat wearing a hat like that and
pulling a rope. Play it.
[Music]
There they are. Here are the children.
Here are the American children.
All we get is Grul. That's okay. Grul's
healthy.
Gro is actually one of the healthiest
things you can eat because it's high
protein and it doesn't have sugar.
See formations.
No one has shoes. They don't care. They
don't uniforms. You hold your bowl. You
get your You get your goodness.
All right. All right. We get it. This
Listen, what So where where would you
rather them? shooting up
schools, selling doing drugs, running
around the mall with guns. That's what
the kids are doing. They're running
around the mall now with a
gun. Work. I think we're getting rid of
child labor laws. Get them in a job,
these
kids. Children should be able to work at
factories.
Sorry. Teens sentenced for their roles
in smash and grabs because Yeah, let's
watch it. Because they have no
community. They have no sense of pride
in in in the in the things they make.
Let's watch this. Guns after using
stolen vehicles to smash their way right
into those stores. Thanks for joining us
here at 6. I'm Mike Dardis and good
evening to you. I'm Sheree Palo. Today
in Claremont County, the last of those
teenagers who pleaded guilty to charges
learned their sentences. Our WLWT
News5's Brian Ham was in the courtroom
for the deposition hearing and has more
live tonight. Hi Brian. That looks like
a magician.
Hey, Sheree. Yeah, we have three
juveniles, three different sentences.
They were all uh caught in these smash
and grab style uh burglaries where they
used a stolen car to do the smashing.
This is where where the wheels came off
in the crime right here in Claremont
County. They were caught shortly after a
robbery in this plaza and today they
were sentenced.
It was a summer of smashing. It's a
really bad situation. All right. But
this is what's happening with the
children are criminals. The children in
this country are c Look at what they're
doing. This is what the children in the
country are doing. The children in the
country are criminals. And we need to
get back to a time when they delivered
the paper. Remember when they would
deliver the paper? Get up newsies. Get
newsies up. They would deliver the
paper and you'd have a paper route and
you'd get up early and you didn't want
to do it, but your your parents would
tell you you you get on that bike and
you deliver the paper and it gave you a
sense of pride and you'd get a shiny
coin and then you would use it at the
fair to buy your lady a
uh I don't know, a cotton candy or
something. This is what we're going back
to. Look at Look at this.
Look at this.
How happy. Look at this. Hot off the
presses.
Everyone's happy. Everyone's happy.
[Music]
This is what it used to be. This is the
country that it used to be like.
Tariffs get us back to this.
Look at this. They can The kids now are
too fat. They can't even jump. Look at a
horse pulling a trolley. This is what we
can go back to. Dancing in the street.
All right, here's my point. We're we're
we're going back to when you used to go
to a diner with your
woman and you would smoke a cigarette at
a diner and eat a cheeseburger. Okay?
You wouldn't vape and then eat a veggie
burger in some [__] uh trans uh
communist safe house. You would go to a
diner like a man and smoke a Marbor
Red. And then we're going back to the
good times and we're going to invade
Vietnam. We're going we're gonna we can
win it now. We can win it now.
So many people I know have online
businesses and I'm telling you right now
the thing you want to really think about
is like the most important part of the
business, the origination of clients,
the uh you know products you're selling.
You don't want to think about the back
office stuff, right? So at the end of
the day, I think you need to use Ship
Station. It's so easy to automate
shipping tasks and manage orders in one
simple dashboard. I love that automation
allows you to smoothly print shipping
labels at the click of a button. You've
been able to let people scale their
businesses faster because Ship Station's
robust automation and reporting. It
feels great to save thousands on
shipping with industryleading discounts
from their rate shopper. I'm telling
you, it's the fastest, most affordable
way to ship products to your customers
with discounts up to 88% off UPSd
Express and USPS rates up to 90% off
FedEx rates. Calm the chaos of order
fulfillment with the shipping software
that delivers. Switch to Shipstation
today. Go to shipstation.com. Use code
Tim Dylan to sign up for your free
trial. that
shipstation.com code Tim Dylan s hi p s
t a t io n.com code tim dillan t iim d i
l l o
n I mean I'm excited about where this
country is going. I'm not worried. I
think we need a bit of
nostalgia and and a market crash might
be necessary to just get people to
appreciate what matters in life.
What matters in life is not your 401k
plan. It's that your family works at a
factory and it is they are they can be
good
jobs. They can be a good
job. You
can't you can't have it
all. There is going to be classes in
society. At the bottom is going to be
the kind of like, you know, drug
addled, sporadic youth gangs and, you
know, the
unhoused, the
homeless, the
terrorists, people that are just on the
margins. And then you're going to have
the great vast middle of factory workers
who are making things. And then at the
top of society, you will have finance,
tech, and podcasters who will occupy the
top spaces in our society. People like
me who have the courage to sit behind a
desk and fatly scream about the things I
barely understand. That is the way
society functions now. I don't
understand what people are say. The vast
middle of this country needs something
to do. Okay. Federal Reserve uh board
member Philip Jefferson claimed that
there were no plans to change track on
the two plan cuts for this year because
Wall Street was like, "Well, maybe tank
the rates, tank the interest rates to
offset some of the bleeding in the
market." No, no, no, no,
no. We're not doing it. Get up Willy
Wonka. Get up the Oompa Loompas. Look at
the Oompa. What if you told the Oompa
Loompas, "By the way, the chocolate
factories closed. Now you're all gonna
bartend at the Capitol Grill. They can't
even see over the bar in the Capitol
Grill. They're Oompa Loompas. Okay. What
we've done in this country is tell a
bunch of Oompa Loompas that we're going
to make the chocolate in China now where
they don't even believe in God. So now
you've got a bunch of orange people
running around on fentinyl. They're
upset. They're not invested in the
market. The assetowning class has taken
all the money and the Oompa Loompas are
just trying to get on reality shows or
flick their bean on only fans. They've
got fentanyl needles out of their arms
and their kids are doing smash and
grabs. No good.
I've got a perfect puzzle for you.
Now this is H. Now pause this. Now
they're doing this in
India. That's India.
Now what? We're doing this in India.
We're doing it in China.
This is footage from a real fact. Now
people, oh, it's a movie. It's a movie.
Shut up. It was a real This is This is
as close to what I can show you as to
what life used to be like when people
had purpose. Go.
Eating as much as an elephant eats. What
are you at getting terribly fat? What do
you think will come of that?
I don't like the look of it. They're
very judgmental for people who work in a
chocolate factory. I've never listened
to the words of this before. A little
fat phobic, isn't it? To be, you know,
aren't they? Aren't they the ones?
Aren't they making the chocolate and
yelling at everyone for eating
it? But what I mean is that they had a
community, they had a life, they had
things going on. The Oompa- Loompa could
have a a little it could have a wife and
then he could have Oompa Loompa
children. Now we say to the Oompa
Loompas, I hope you got your uh
Bitcoin. Oh, are you invested in uh uh
crypto? No, no, no, no, no. I'm trying
to make the chocolate bar. Oh, we don't
do that here anymore. Sorry. The
factories in
China. Go work at Panera. So that that's
what America is. It's an Oompa Loompa at
Panera who's pissed off. Who's making
your little uh you know panini at
Panera? They put it. Do you want to heat
it up? You want to heat it up? Do you
want to heat it up? They're not happy.
They used to go to a factory and sing
and make treats for the children. Now
they're in a strip mall in a Panera
waiting to get shot in the face by a
psychopath. You want it? You want it
heated? Do you want What soup do you
want? We have southwestern corn chowder.
It's so horrible what we've done to
people cuz these balooas. Now follow me
here because I know many of you are I
think most of the people watches are
high on something so it's easier to get
to where I'm going. But some of them are
sober like me. And if you are sober, you
have to follow me a little bit. What
you're doing now is this. These tariffs
are for the Oompa Loompas because Wonka
they came to Wonka. Chinese came to
Wanka and they said, "You're a
psychopath. You're going to keep paying
these Oompa Loompas to make the
chocolate for the children." And Wanka
goes, "Well, I'm going to give the
factory to Charlie cuz he's worthy of
it. And he's going to keep everything
going." Well, maybe maybe Charlie goes,
you know, I looked at the books. We
opened it up. And here's the reality.
Even though Willy Wonka is a genius, he
didn't know what he was doing with
business. is factories on the edge of
bankruptcy. We need to cut costs. We
need to cut costs. We can no longer
afford to produce the chocolate in the
factory. We need to go to where labor
costs are low. So, we're moving the
factory. We're moving it to China or
we're moving it to uh
Pakistan. So, the factory goes goodbye
by. Then a real estate developer gets
rid of the Willy Wonka chalk. They keep
a little of it because you want the gate
and the thing and they build a condo
where the chocolate factory used to be,
but they keep just enough of it to
excite the millionaires and billionaires
who are going to buy these condos. They
come in to the chocolate factory and
they go, "Oh, I'm living in this new
building and it's so [__] cool." And
the realtors go, "They are developing
the Willy Wonka Chocolate Factory into a
luxury
condo." And then all of their clients,
many of them foreign, buy condos in the
Willy Wonka Chocolate Factory that they
visit a few months out of the year. They
don't
care. They don't care. And you know
what? All is left of the chocolate
factory, a couple of uh murals on the
wall of
chocolate. Okay. But just chocolate.
They don't they don't show Willie or the
Oompa Loompas cuz people would ask when
they were in the lobby, where did the
Oompa Loompas go? Oh, they're on heroin.
They're on
heroin. So the Oompa Loompas now that
are told to [__] off. Charlie takes a
big buyout. Okay. Because a
multinational corporation like Unilver
buys the chocolate factory and they move
all of the jobs offshore. Charlie gets a
big penthouse and sits at the top of the
penthouse and he Yeah. Him him. He's now
evil. Okay. Cuz he said, "I need more
money and more money and more." And he
never even liked chocolate. That's the
other thing. He didn't even like
chocolate. He'd just like going to
orgies on a yacht in international
waters. So then he's at the top of his
penthouse and he goes, "Oh, are we?
Let's go to the orgy. I'll take the
helicopter. We'll land right on the
yacht." So now he's in international
waters having orgies with all of his
winnings because Unilver bought the
chocolate factory and shipped it to
China, India, Brazil. And people call
you from India and ask you if you want
chocolate around Valentine's Day and
they'll ship it to you cuz they have
distribution centers in America that
ship the Chinese-made chocolate to your
fat wife. Okay. So now Charlie's a
gazillionaire babillionaire. He's a
zillionaire and he's flying his
helicopter and landing on a yacht where
he has sex with underage women and then
cuts their throat at the point of orgasm
and throws them over the yacht and then
they all die in the ocean which is also
pollution and he's sitting at the top of
the factory and all of the oompalooas
are working at Panera and they're strung
out. Okay, follow me here. Don't start
with me.
All these strung out Oompa Loompas are
like, "Fuck, what's the deal?" And they
ask Charlie about this. They say,
"Charlie, why did you do this?" And he
he comes back, he wipes the blood off
himself from just throwing a woman over
a boat. And they said, "Charlie, why did
you sell the factory? Why are all the
oompalooas on fentinol?" And Charlie
says, "It's a shame how trans people are
treated in this country." And they go,
"What?" And he goes, "It's disgusting
how trans people." And he go, "Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, but but but
Charlie, the Oompa Loompas are all on
fentanyl and they're eating at Panera
and they're dying." And Charlie goes,
"Well, the CEO of Unilever is a trans
woman and she's a woman." And he go,
"But I don't understand, Charlie. We
don't really have problems with trans
people, but many of the loompas are now
hanging themselves with these little
ropes because they have no jobs. and
you're you're just offshore on some
yacht and whatever. I don't know. And
you're invested in all these different
companies, but you know, we had a thing
here. We had a chocolate factory where
we would sing and be happy and all the
families would get together and they'd
have a little chocolate every now and
then. And people used to walk around and
be proud of the downtown because it was
a chocolate factory and there was
tourism and there was a sense of
community. And Charlie goes, "Hey man,
I'm a little sick of white guys." And
you go, "But Charlie, Charlie, you're
like really white. You're like pale."
And he goes, "And I'm ashamed of it."
And then he gets on his helicopter and
murders another woman. And it almost
feels like Charlie himself is using some
of this, okay,
to get people's mind off the fact that
he sold his chocolate factory to a
global multinational conglomerate who's
offshored all of the
jobs. Okay? And then Charlie's sitting
there and he's saying, "Hey man, this is
just the way it is. Those Oompa Loompas
need to diversify their portfolios." And
the Oompa Loompa is like, "Wait, what?
I'm covered in corn chowder at a Panera.
I I think people try to kill me. The
lemonades caused two heart attacks this
last month." And people go, "Yeah, man,
but you're a [__] racist." And the
Oompa Loompa goes, "Well, I'm not really
a racist, but I just have my my life has
been made horrible, and I don't know how
it happened. You know, I'm a third
generation Oompa-Loompa. I'm trained in
the chocolate manufacturing." And people
go, "Yeah, whatever, man. I don't know.
You just seem like some kind of Nazi."
And you go, I I don't know about that. I
just I don't get healthcare at this
Panera and my wife's sick. She has
headaches. We don't know what they are,
but they keep coming and they go, "Hey,
man. I just don't understand like why
you have to keep harping on uh
immigrants." And you go, I don't really
care about immigrants. I just I just
want some type of job. I I want some
type of future in this country. And they
go, well, I don't know about that. I
don't know about that,
bucko. Do you want it hot? We can make
the sandwich hot. Do you want it hot? Do
you want it heated
up? So then someone's elected and they
say, "We want to bring the chocolate
factory back to America, but it's
complicated." Well, why is it
complicated? Well,
[__] Because Charlie wasn't the only
one who sold the chocolate factory. In
fact, Santa
Claus is no longer making the toys at
the North Pole. Do you know who's making
the toys? The people in
Taiwan are making the toys. Fine. Okay.
She go,
"Well, Santa shut down the toy shop and
it's being made by people in Taiwan."
And that's fine and great for them. But
what happened to the elves? Well, the
elves and the Oompa Loompas are on the
internet reading about maybe the earth
is flat because they don't have enough
money to take their kids uh to uh Disney
World or whatever. So now we've
abandoned the elves and the Oompa
Loompas.
Okay? And we we we're yelling at them
and screaming at them and and wondering
why they're becoming increasingly
politically radical and volatile and why
they're embracing pathological behavior.
We we don't understand it. But Santa
Claus is in Miami living in a penthouse
with Ken
Griffin. And Santa's like, "I was an
early investor in Citadel and I've
always believed in Ken." And and that's
lovely and
nice for Santa. He goes, "Ah, the toy
business ain't what it used to And
Santa's just sitting there in Bal Harbor
in a
7bedroom, 7b condo overlooking the
ocean. Maybe at the ocean. I don't know.
Who cares? But Santa's sick of the cold.
He likes Miami because there's no income
taxes. And there's plenty of Latin
American women that he can
[Music]
ogle. So Willy
Wonka gave the factory to Charlie who
gave it to Unilver. Santa gave the toy
shop to
Taiwan. The Oompa Loompas and the elves
have been left to fend for themselves
and they are all working at
Panera. So then Donald Trump goes, I
want to bring the chocolate factory and
Santa's workshop back. But the problem
is that our entire economy is based on
the fact that everything we consume is
made by child
slaves. That's why it's also goddamn
cheap. Why do you think it's cheap? You
think it's cheap? Because people these
factories Fox Con and they're not good
at Amazon either. You're not allowed to
use the bathroom.
The whole thing is a nightmare because
in order for maximum productivity, you
have to treat human beings like they're
uh you know slaves, like they're
indentured servants, like they don't
have any autonomy or agency. And the way
to do that is to destroy any type of
union and any type of community that
these people had. Every one of my
friends is unneutral. I'm telling you,
they have thicker, fuller heads of hair.
I'm telling you, it's easy for us guys
to overlook our own well-being. Many of
us are so busy, we don't realize the
stress from inside can affect the
outside. If you've been noticing a
little less hair when you look in the
mirror lately, now is a perfect time to
start taking Neutrifol. You can improve
your hair growth from the inside out.
Hair thinning is very common, very
frustrating problem that many men deal
with. From stress and nutrition to
hormone and lifestyle, so many internal
factors affect what you see on the
outside. Luckily, Neutrifll is here to
help.
Neutrifil is the number one
dermatologist recommended hair growth
supplement brand trusted by over one and
a half million people in just three to
six months. Go from a hat guy to a hair
guy with thicker, stronger, faster
growing hair with less shedding.
Neutrifull's hair growth supplements are
physician formulated using 100%
drug-free ingredients. Their patented
technology provides consistent, reliable
results. Men also reported no compromise
in their sexual performance. Start your
hair growth journey with Neutrifll. For
a limited time, Neutrifol is offering
our listeners $10 off your first month
subscription and free shipping when you
go to
neutrfull.com/men and enter the promo
code TimDillan. That's
neutrfull.com/men. Promo code TimDillan.
Find out why 4,500 healthcare
professionals and stylists recommend
Neutrifll for healthier hair.
neutrfll.com/men spelled
nutrfol.com/men promo code TimDillan.
That's
neutrfull.com. Neutrifold.commen promo
code Tim DDan. So these
tariffs are maybe probably long-term
potentially good, but maybe in the short
term they're going to be absolutely a
mess. And maybe long term it won't even
work either. I don't know, and I'm not
an economist. What I do know is that the
people who've hollowed out the country,
who've shipped the jobs elsewhere, who
turned their back to child slaves while
tweeting about social causes they happen
to like and find
important. Those people are now very
spooked because the economy is a scam
and a fraud. And and now
We don't know what to do. And I'm not
saying it's going to be good. I'm not
saying you're going to be able to go
back to the Oompa Loompa chocolate
factory because these Oompa Loompas have
a lot of tattoos now. No one loves that.
You know, it's just too many tattoos.
It's like, what is this? What are you
doing? And the Oompa Loompas are upset
and the elves are upset and you know, so
we're gambling. The gambit here. the the
the the gamble that Trump's probably
staking his entire presidency on is that
he can get people like
Charlie who got the chocolate factory
because he won some dumb ticket. Okay.
And his sick grandpa and him wandered
around and supposedly he's a good
person. Is he? What happened to the
women on the yacht? Few of them didn't
make it
back. So what we're saying here and I'm
doing this by the way in front of
Congress. I'm workshopping this here,
but I'm doing this in front of a joint
session. I'm doing it in front of a
joint session of Congress. I actually
am. Have I explained you what's going
on? I hope I have. And we're trying to
go back to the good old days or what we
thought was the good old days. And maybe
they were never the good old days, but
they were better days for workingclass
Americans than they are now. And it's
hard. Our economy is run by an int
intelligence agencies and international
criminals.
Do you understand that? That there is no
such thing as an economy. Stop it.
You're It's
fake. It's
fake. So they can arrange it, make it do
whatever it
wants. You're going to What's that
apartment? It $200 million. No, it's
not. It's fake. It's all fake. It's
money laundering. It's criminality. It's
blackmail. It's the intelligence
agencies and a lot of their friends high
up in finance and tech arranging the
world in ways that allow them to win.
They're trying to eliminate human
beings. It's just what it is. These
tariffs might be a mess. These tariffs
are probably economically bad
short-term, potentially
long-term. But when we talk about the
economy, understand what we're talking
about. We're talking about an
international system where criminals
thrive at the expense of human
beings, a class of biological entity
they'd like to eliminate as soon as
possible. I don't even want to get into
how much the intelligence community
controls the economy. That's a whole
another episode. I know more about it
than I should. I've spoke to some very
smart people about
it. Okay.
They're
everywhere. And I I'm not saying that in
a paranoid way, but what I'm saying is
like, yes, it is an international
interdependent system. Yes, our cars are
made with parts that come from Canada.
Yes, iPhones are made with parts that
come from 100 plus countries. Yes, it is
an interconnected globalized world. But
don't forget who's benefiting the most
from that. We have a limited social
safety net in this country. We don't
have healthcare. We don't have
retirement. We don't have a lot of these
things. We don't guarantee a lot of
standard of living for people. We have
401k plans and some of them got beat up
and that does suck
thousand%. But we've thrown the American
working class as as a lot of people have
said, we've threw them out in the cold
and these tariffs are a way to try to
wrestle that back. I don't know if it'll
work. I don't know what happens if you
open the chocolate factory again.
I do know that in the chocolate factory
now you have luxury
condos that people are living in. They
live in the chocolate factory. Five
blocks away from the chocolate factory.
There are people oding on the
street, but they clear those bodies up
so you don't have to step over them as
you get into the chocolate factory. The
chocolate factory, for example, has dark
wood. The color palette of the chocolate
factory condo, ironically enough, is
kind of chocolate. They have milk
chocolate wood or dark chocolate. Which
color palette do you want? You've made
your money in
finance. That's a $21
million industrial loft in the chocolate
factory. And it's owned by the daughter
of a Chinese amusement park tycoon who's
rarely seen. She goes there with a few
of her art school friends to do coke.
I'm describing the world. Pay attention.
I don't have time. You understand me? I
have to go to
Vegas. Trying to play
bakarat. My godson's coming to the hotel
I'm staying at. I could give him money.
I just paid for his school. I thought he
was Chinese. Then they go oh he's
Filipino. It's like what are we doing?
Why is he in a Why is he in a
Montasauri? He's Filipino. Goes right to
work. Sounds racist, but it's not
actually
not. And they're going to shoot, they're
going to kill Luigi uh whatever his name
is, Penny Alavka. They're going to kill
Manion. And they're going to kill Luigi
Manion, not only because he's hot, but
because he shot this
guy and he had a lot of popular support.
Because people are like, "I'm sick of
watching my family die because they're
broke. I'm sick of watching people die
that don't live in the chocolate factory
condo for $20 million that don't have
concierge doctors that don't have
medicine. I'm I'm sick of that." And
maybe Manion is not the perfect mascot
for this. Maybe Manion was just a hot
guy who couldn't [__] who got mad and
shot a guy. I don't really know. Maybe
that's what it's shaping up to be. Is he
the hero you want? No. No one's the hero
you think they are. It doesn't matter.
Doesn't matter. We're trying to turn
back the clock with these tariffs, but
what I'm trying to tell you is it's
going to be very difficult. It's going
to be very hard. The world isn't the
world by accident. Nothing developed the
way it did out of happen stance. It has
been a takeover for a very long
time. People have been sold the idea
that freedom is the ultimate thing in
life. Most people want communities,
families, and security. But we've
supplanted. We go freedom. You can have
all the jobs or none of the jobs. You
can do whatever you want and live
wherever you want. You can invest in
anything you want. Isn't it great? You
can deliver food and you can Uber and
have an Only Fans and a blog and a
podcast. You could do it all. You're a
media entity. You are who you've been
waiting for. You don't need anybody
else. You can go to school online or
offline or a brickandmortar, whatever
you like. It doesn't matter. You could
team up with a bunch of people and start
a YouTube channel where you review
architecture from old houses that are
now abandoned and that crackheads live
in because we ship the chocolate factory
away. You have all the freedom in the
world, but none of the security, none of
the benefits. We've given you all the
freedom, all the pretend freedom that
you wouldn't know what to do with. And
it's not designed for you to actually
use Donald
Trump. Here's the thing, and I'll get in
trouble for saying this. I don't know if
this will
work, but he's not
wrong. I don't know if it'll work, but
he's not wrong.
I passed a chocolate factory the other
day and it is silly to think about that
kind of America coming back. It's why we
started with the newsies and the this
and the that. And it is funny and it is
silly the idea of people having a job
and security. It is silly to think
about. It is funny. It is
strange. But we've given you freedom and
we've taken everything else away.
We're a scambased economy. Do I love the
Trump crypto [__] Absolutely not. Do I
love some of his new tech friends? We
know how I feel. I'm not going to be the
ad nauseium guy that annoys everybody
with
it. But I'm telling you right now, we're
selling you
freedom, but we're not really selling
you freedom. The word we're selling
you is chaos.
You're mistaking freedom for chaos. You
think that you are free to do anything
you want, but you're free to gamble.
You're free to hedge your bets. You're
free chaos, disorder,
confusion. That's what we mean by
freedom. a manic attempt to survive.
Your spiritual life, your emotional
well-being, your mental health, your
sexual health, all of these things are
suffering because you're scrambling to
survive and put money in your bank
account. But we've convinced you that
that's an actual great state of being.
That insanity, that mania is great.
We've sold it to you as
Americana. We've sold that to you. Now,
that is a part of America. A lot of
people, myself included, I have an
addict brain. I got into
comedy. It's worked, but for years it
didn't. I started making money at 35.
I'm now 40. I've had five years of
earning money. I had a 10-year career
before that where I didn't earn any
money. Didn't earn a lot of money.
It was me and Stavros performing at Joe
List's uh thing and we loved it. And by
the way, it was the most fun in the
world. So I I I don't regret any of it.
It was actually a lot of
fun. There are people that are going to
just want to take risks and do crazy
things and you know whether they pan out
or not. I was very lucky. I was lucky. I
was able to do it. I had to I wasn't you
know I didn't have to I mean uh I had a
good enough health to do it. I mean I'm
not a triathlete but I had good enough
health to do standup.
What I'm saying is
that this
idea that the stock market runs our
lives, that
chaos is
freedom, and that you have to be in a
manic state of reinventing
yourself. This
entrepreneurship horeshit that has been
sold to you as if a business is better
than a family. as if an empire is better
than truly knowing who you are as a
human being. It's essential to sell that
to you so that Larry Frink and Black
Rockck can steal
everything. And that's why they pump all
these gurus that tell you how to make
money and steal and all this [__]
And I'm not against money and I love
money. And no one who says they don't
love money is uh
true. But understand where it comes
from. Donald Trump is [__] the
economy up, but he's not wrong. Those
two things are both true. I'm sorry for
you to hear that. I know a lot of people
don't want to hear it. He's he's [__]
it up right now. But he's not
wrong. If you were to look at what's
happened to the country, if you were to
look at the economic and
cultural
malaise that the working class has felt,
something has to be done. Is it
realistic to get them all back into
factories? I I don't know. I don't plan
to be I'm I'm not claiming to be an
expert here. But what I'm telling you is
at the end at the end of the day, if
Larry Frink and Black Rockck are telling
you something is good for you, you know,
the company that bought all the
houses, it's probably not.
If they're selling you freedom, but
they're giving you
instability, they're giving you chaos,
they're telling you that the gig economy
is great, there Larry Frink comes out
and says, "You should invest more money.
Don't save it. Invest it.
Gamble, give it to me. Give it to us."
us and he came out and he said
that if he's out there telling
you that you're being too
cautious or responsible with your
money, you know, there's a reason for
it. Open Phone is the number one
business phone system that streamlines
and scales your customer communications.
Every time you miss a call, you're
losing money, folks. You're leaving
money on the table. If you're running a
business, every missed call is a
potential loss of revenue. Think about
the last time you had a plumbing
emergency. If the first plumber didn't
answer, did you wait or call the next
one on the list? Chances are you moved
on. It works through an app on your
phone or computer, so no more carrying
two phones or using a landline. With
Open Phone, your team can share one
number and collaborate on customer calls
and texts like a shared inbox. That way,
any teammate can pick up right where the
last person left off, keeping response
times faster than ever. Plus, with AI
powered call transcripts and summaries,
you'll be able to automate follow-ups,
ensuring you'll never miss a customer
interaction again. So, whether you're a
one-person operation drowning in calls
and texts, or have a large team that
needs better collaboration tools, Open
Phone is a no-brainer. Open Phone is
offering my listeners 20% off your first
6 months at
openphone.com/tim. That's
oph.com/tim. And if you have existing
numbers with another service, open
phone, we'll port them over at no extra
charge. Open phone. No missed calls, no
missed customers. Springtime is here and
baseball season is officially underway.
Don't miss your chance to add to your
favorite players from the diamond in
your prize pick lineup. Whether it's
strikeouts, RBI's, or first inning runs,
take your picks of more or less for your
shot to win up to a thousand times your
cash today. Prize Picks is the best way
to get action on sports in more than 30
states, including California, Texas,
Georgia. This app is really easy to use.
To create a lineup, all you have to do
is pick more or less on a player stats
for your shot to win up to a thousand
times your money. Prize Pix is the best
place to win cash while watching sports.
Join over 10 million users and sign up
today. On Prize Pix, you can mix and
match player projections from different
sports. Combine your favorite baseball
players with players from basketball,
hockey, esports, and much more. Sign up
today and get $50 instantly when you
play $5. You don't even need to win to
receive the $50 bonus. It's guaranteed.
Prize Pix also offers weekly promotions
that can lead to big payouts like Taco
Tuesday each Tuesday. Prize picks
discount selected player projections up
to 25% off to provide even more value
for your lineups. Download the app today
and use code TIM to get $50 instantly
when you play your first $5 lineup.
Download the app today to use code TIM
to get $50 instantly after you play your
first $5 lineup. Prize picks run your
game. Prize picks run your game. Prize
picks run your
game. I'm not saying these tariffs are
going to work. I'm not saying these
tariffs are good.
But I don't think we can run a country
where we turn all the chocolate
factories into high-end condos that are
sold to the daughters of Chinese
amusement park
tycoons who only go every now and then
to do Coke with their art school
friends. Art, by the way, a lot of it
fake. I'm just saying. Santa's in
Miami. The elves are working at Jamba
Juice. making
smoothies. It doesn't work for a long
time. The middle falls out. People feel
disconnected. You usher them into cyber
bubbles where they can only live through
the internet. They can only express
their emotions and the only freedom they
really have is to go on X or Instagram
and
post. We tell them it no longer makes
sense to own a house. Why would you own
a car? Just Uber. Just
rent. Just be somebody
online. That's all we need you to do. We
don't want you to own land. We do not
want you to own a car. I don't know if
these tariffs are going to work. What I
know is that the world that was ushered
in by Charlie who let down Willy Wonka
because he sold that factory to
Unilver. Does Uni Lever advertise on
this show? I better watch my mouth. I
don't think they
do. Look at that. Look, I want you to
look at that because I'll tell you what
Charlie's
seeing. He's looking at that golden
ticket. You know what he's
seeing? He's seeing an invitation to the
party. That's what little Charlie is
seeing. He goes, "One day I can wear a
goat head and stomp around in the forest
of California and kill people." You know
what Charlie's seeing? He's seeing a $38
million penthouse in Monaco where they
have no income tax and no property tax.
I did think about moving the studio
there. Charlie's thinking about a yacht
where he can disappear Ukrainian women
after he's done with them. Charlie is
not seeing in that golden ticket what
you think he's seeing. You think he's
seeing the pride of owning the factory,
the children getting the treats, the
softball team, the family. Charlie's not
seeing any of that. He's thinking of how
quickly and he can sell this company
right out from under the Oompa Loompas
who've stirred those pots of chocolate.
And all Charlie wants to do is go on
MSNBC with CIA director John Brennan and
talk about how deeply ashamed he is at
racism or something or whatever is
they're going to focus you on instead of
the fact that the Oompa Loompa in Panera
was just shot by a child.
The Oompa Loompa in Panera just got shot
in the face by a
child. So what does it all
mean? The answers
aren't. The answers aren't
apparent. Three teenage
girls try to stab their mother for
turning off the Wi-Fi.
That's where we're at. That's where
we're at in this country. Three teenage
girls tried to stab their mother for
trying to turn off the Wi-Fi. Let's
watch a little bit of this.
Well, three teenage girls are in custody
tonight after police say they plan to
kill their own mother. And they say that
it's all because their mom turned off
the Wi-Fi. It happened overnight on
Barker's Crossing near Barker Cypress in
northwest Harris County. That's where we
find Fox 26's Jade Flurry on this
disturbing story.
Jade. Well, fortunately, the Harris
County Sheriff's Office says that the
teen's mom was not seriously injured
after her own daughters tried to stab
her with knives. And we spoke with some
nearby neighbors who tell us that
disturbances happen frequently at the
family home. They're known for that in
this neighborhood. There it's always
cops around that house. A family dispute
turned violent. The Harris County
Sheriff's Office says a mother was
assaulted by her own teenage daughters
for turning off the Wi-Fi. Authorities
alleged the girls then plotted to kill
her. The three teens, ages 14, 15, and
16 years old, accused of grabbing
kitchen knives and chasing their mom
throughout the house and into the
street. A nearby neighbor says they were
returning from the rodeo when they saw
the family in the driveway moments
later. The country is clearly very sick
and we have lots of
problems. These are the
problems. The kids are trying to kill
the parents for turning off the
Wi-Fi. I don't think that's good. Do
you? So, in
summation, I don't know how this is
going to play out. Nobody knows how it's
going to play out. What I've just
described to you is as accurate a vision
of the world as I can. That's the world
as it is. That's what it is. Charlie,
the chocolate factory condo, the yacht
in Monaco with the Ukrainian women who
disappear, and the Chinese amusement
park tycoon's daughter who does coke
occasionally with her art school
friends. That's what it is.
There's not there's not a ton more to
say. How do you wind the clock
back so that the oompalooas are walking
happily into the chocolate factory? I
don't
know. I don't
know. But I know that
Charlie is just a
guy who was once a
kid who once remembered how good it was
to eat chocolate and how fun it was to
get a chance to visit the
factory before he became a vicious
marquee murderer who killed Ukrainian
women on a yacht in international
waters.
while he earned the money off his
unilver
deal. Was he born like
that or was he born a good kid? Did we
turn him into that guy? Did we turn him
into a guy who lands helicopters on a
yacht just so he can stab a few
women? Was there another version of
Charlie? Is it religion? Is it politics?
Is it culture? Is it all things?
That's all I'm asking. At what point did
Charlie go wrong? At what point did
Charlie forget that he was part of a
larger picture and that we all
owe it to ourselves to look outside of
ourselves.
Okay? Go to the end of Willy Wonka. Go
to the end of it because it's important.
These things are
important. This is
what the tariffs really mean. Let's
watch this. Let's watch this a
little. Mr. Walker, I am extraordinarily
busy. Sir, I just wanted to ask about
the
chocolate. The lifetime supply of
chocolate for
Charlie. Well, when does he get it? He
doesn't. Why not? Because he broke the
rules. There's a little bit when it gets
good. What rules? Cuz we know he tricks
him and everything. Wrong. He tricks him
in a weary world. Go to the end where
they get up in that thing. Here he is.
Here he is. Here he is. He goes, "Now
this Charlie is London." And then
Charlie looks at it and he goes, "One
day we'll kick all these people out of
these [__] houses.
We'll kick all these [__] lazy
scumbags out of these
houses and we'll turn them into condos
and brothel. You can see it in Charlie's
eyes. I think it's the most wonderful
place. He goes, "And they'll just be
houses where people live stream all day
and all these people will die and we'll
import people from other places that'll
do the work cheaper and they'll make the
chocolate and then eventually we'll just
sell the whole goddamn factory." And
anyone who complains about this will be
called a Nazi. But I'll be on a yacht in
Monaco having just filleted a Ukrainian
woman like a fish because that's the
only way I can come. Find a child.
My name is Tim Dylan. This is the Tim
Dylan Show. I have a special on Netflix
April
15th. This probably isn't for everyone,
this content. I I I I understand that.
But this is as good of a job as I can
do. You can go to the Stern School of
Business. You can go to UPEN. What I
just did is more valuable than both of
those
institutions. Bye.